<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vmware on Funky Cloud Medina</title>
    <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vmware/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vmware on Funky Cloud Medina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016-2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vmware/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>VclAbstractObjectValue - Unable to serialize object</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/vclabstractobjectvalue---unable-to-serialize-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/vclabstractobjectvalue---unable-to-serialize-object/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been working on some automation that will create metadata against objects in vCloud Director using vRealize Orchestrator. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever had to do this before you&amp;rsquo;ll know how painful it can be to get your head around all of the objects/transformations you need to make before you can even set the metadata to the object.
First you take the metadata value (in this case a string) and create a new VclMetadataStringValue object.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director metrics - unable to configure metric, conflicts with existing column</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/vcloud-director-metrics---unable-to-configure-metric-conflicts-with-existing-column/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/vcloud-director-metrics---unable-to-configure-metric-conflicts-with-existing-column/</guid>
      <description>Recently I spent some time configuring vCloud Director metrics and storing them in a Cassandra cluster. If you have ever stepped outside of the default metrics and tried to provide your own via a Groovy file, you may have hit the following error in the cell-management-tool.log log:
Invalid column name **metric** because it conflicts with an existing column  If your Groovy file contains the metric listed in the error message and you&amp;rsquo;ve only listed it once, you&amp;rsquo;re probably thinking &amp;ldquo;where on earth is this duplicate coming from?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NSX Manager upgrade reports: Insufficient disk space</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/nsx-manager-upgrade-reports-insufficient-disk-space/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/08/nsx-manager-upgrade-reports-insufficient-disk-space/</guid>
      <description>Have you got an NSX Manager that&amp;rsquo;s done the rounds for the past few years and served you well? Is it time for another upgrade but you&amp;rsquo;re stuck because the disk is full and you&amp;rsquo;ve been told:
Cannot continue upgrade due to errors : Insufficient disk space. Database disk usage is at 87%, but it should be less than 70%. We recommend running a database full vacuum before proceeding with upgrade.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vRealize Operations Manager - Outbound REST Notification log location</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/03/vrealize-operations-manager---outbound-rest-notification-log-location/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/03/vrealize-operations-manager---outbound-rest-notification-log-location/</guid>
      <description>A quick post today! I was trying to configure the vRealize Operations Manager Outbound REST notification plugin recently and I was having a few issues doing a POST or PUT operation against the specified endpoint. Specifically, I was getting the following message:
 Test was not successful: Failed to post or put to the server.
 I tried looking around the vROPs Logs section under Administration &amp;gt; Support &amp;gt; Logs but couldn&amp;rsquo;t find anything specific for Outbound Notification plugins.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Enumerate vRO Workflow Inputs into a JSON object</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/02/enumerate-vro-workflow-inputs-into-a-json-object/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/02/enumerate-vro-workflow-inputs-into-a-json-object/</guid>
      <description>Just this week I had to create a JSON object that contained all of the workflow input parameters and their respective values. While I can&amp;rsquo;t guarantee this is the best way to do it, it definitely works.
I&amp;rsquo;ve tried to keep the comments succinct so if you have any questions please ask.
Code // Get all input parameters for the parent workflow var inParamsArray = workflow.rootWorkflow.inParameters; // Get all input parameters for the current workflow to search through later var paramFinder = workflow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CassandraDB Shell - Unable to connect to any servers</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/cassandradb-shell---unable-to-connect-to-any-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/cassandradb-shell---unable-to-connect-to-any-servers/</guid>
      <description>One of the core pre-requisites for vCloud Availability for vCloud Director 2.0 is CassandraDB. This database service stores replication state and storage information and is used by the HCS (vSphere Replication Cloud Service) appliance.
As part of my strained vCloud Availability deployment I needed to build a simple CassandraDB server. VMware Docs and the vCloud Architecture blog have some great information to get you started:
 vCloud Architecture blog - Deploying CassandraDB VMware Docs - vCloud Availability for vCloud Director Installation Guide  Symptom I built the CassandraDB server as described in the blog post and Docs pages above, but when I would try to connect to the database using the Cassandra shell (cqlsh {ip-address} 9042) I would get the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Availability - vCD Gateway creation failed</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/vcloud-availability---vcd-gateway-creation-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/vcloud-availability---vcd-gateway-creation-failed/</guid>
      <description>After a short break over Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s I threw myself into the latest version of vCloud Availability for vCloud Director (2.0).
The installation of vCloud Availability for vCloud Director (vCAv) is all done through an &amp;ldquo;installer appliance&amp;rdquo;, a CLI and a configuration file called a &amp;lsquo;registry&amp;rsquo;. I opted for the &amp;lsquo;automated&amp;rsquo; installation using a registry file and had all of my configuration and VM deployment specs in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Studying for the VCAP6-Design DCV</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/08/studying-for-the-vcap6-design-dcv/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/08/studying-for-the-vcap6-design-dcv/</guid>
      <description>Here are some of the resources that I worked through as study material for the VCAP6-Design exam. A lot of these links and the discovery of these links can be attributed to a lot of others, and I&amp;rsquo;ll try to credit them where I can.
 vBrownBag EMEA - VCAP6-DCV Design - vBrownBag YouTube channel  Some great presenters here that highlight some of the key concepts and follow up with discussions  vThing - VCAP Study Resources - Andres Herceg&amp;rsquo;s blog https://vthing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>VCAP6-DCV Design certification achieved!</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/vcap6-dcv-design-certification-achieved/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Jul 2017 08:35:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/vcap6-dcv-design-certification-achieved/</guid>
      <description>After months of studying and a Design and Deploy course for good measure, I passed the incredible VCAP6-DCV Design exam!
   This certification in combination with my VCAP5-DCA from 18 months ago has awarded me the VCIX6 title which I&amp;rsquo;m incredibly proud of. Here&amp;rsquo;s the official link from VMware about the certification: https://mylearn.vmware.com/mgrReg/plan.cfm?plan=89125&amp;amp;ui=www_cert
To give you an idea of what the Design exam is about, take a look at www.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CA-signed vCloud Director certificates no longer trusted – SAN missing</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/ca-signed-vcloud-director-certificates-no-longer-trusted--san-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 17:43:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/ca-signed-vcloud-director-certificates-no-longer-trusted--san-missing/</guid>
      <description>Hello again! Today&amp;rsquo;s adventures drove me a little wild&amp;hellip;
Some background first. In my test environment, I have a full vCloud Director v8.10.1 deployment, load balanced with an F5 LTM. The certificates are loaded on the F5 so that traffic is terminated and re-encrypted on it&amp;rsquo;s way to the vCloud cells. Since deployment, both the http and console FQDNs functioned as expected. This all changed just a few months ago&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PSC 6.0U3 not respecting certool.cfg settings when generating VMCA CSR</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/04/psc-6.0u3-not-respecting-certool.cfg-settings-when-generating-vmca-csr/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Apr 2017 17:46:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/04/psc-6.0u3-not-respecting-certool.cfg-settings-when-generating-vmca-csr/</guid>
      <description>After a very successful and quick migration from Windows SSO 5.5 U3e installation to a Platform Services Controller v6.0U3 appliance I was ready to get my VMCA into action.
We have a corporate internal Microsoft CA with the VMware certificate templates already created as per VMware KB 2112009. Everything was coming up Milhouse, until CSR generation time using the &amp;lsquo;certificate-manager&amp;rsquo; on the PSCs.
After stepping through the &amp;lsquo;certificate-manager&amp;rsquo; wizard and having the CSR and private key files sent to a directory of my choosing, I quickly inspected the CSR using openssl to make sure I was on the right track:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Empty inventory after SSO v5.5 to PSC v6.0 U3 migration</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/04/empty-inventory-after-sso-v5.5-to-psc-v6.0-u3-migration/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Apr 2017 07:46:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/04/empty-inventory-after-sso-v5.5-to-psc-v6.0-u3-migration/</guid>
      <description>After performing the vSphere v5.5 to vSphere 6.0 migration in our testing environment with great success, I began work on our production environment. First things first, migrating Windows SSO to PSC appliance.
I had successfully converted the first machine, and started doing some testing. Things like logging into the thick client and checking all vCenter servers and basic login services.
Problem
Out of 6 vCenter servers, only 1 was having issues.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SYSTEM_REFRESH_VIMSERVER – Could not register vCloud Director as an extension to vCenter Server</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/system_refresh_vimserver--could-not-register-vcloud-director-as-an-extension-to-vcenter-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 13:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/system_refresh_vimserver--could-not-register-vcloud-director-as-an-extension-to-vcenter-server/</guid>
      <description>While trying to troubleshoot another problem, we tried Refreshing vCloud to vCenter which includes registering/updating the extension. This is when we hit a beauty we’d never seen before:
   Alright, calm down. Probably something with the network, right? And if it’s not the network then it’s probably DNS. Right? Oh how I wish that were so.
I dug around in the vCenter MOB and found the vCloud Director extension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘java.lang.NullPointerException’ received when modifying objects in vCloud Director</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/java.lang.nullpointerexception-received-when-modifying-objects-in-vcloud-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 11:36:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/java.lang.nullpointerexception-received-when-modifying-objects-in-vcloud-director/</guid>
      <description>Roughly 2 weeks ago one of our vCloud Director tenants reported an error when attempting to increase a disk on their VM. They were told to contact their cloud administrator (yay). When we tried to perform the increase, we received an error we’d never seen before: “java.lang.NullPointerException”.
   Here is what we checked:
 Confirm the tenant Org vDC has the appropriate resources available (this was an ‘Allocation’ style vDC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6 certificate templates with SHA256 encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/01/vsphere-6-certificate-templates-with-sha256-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/01/vsphere-6-certificate-templates-with-sha256-encryption/</guid>
      <description>I was just in the middle of configuring a PSC 6.0 node’s VMCA as an intermediate CA and, in traditional fashion, went to request a certificate from a Windows Server 2008 R2 Microsoft CA using the web enrollment form (as per this VMware KB article).
Oddly enough though my brand spanking new vSphere 6.0 machine and intermediate CA certificate templates were missing from the template selection drop down.
I had a look around online and found that MS CA v3 certificate templates are not supported in the web enrollment form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Export Failed – Converting Windows SSO to PSC Appliance</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/update-export-failed--converting-windows-sso-to-psc-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 17:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/update-export-failed--converting-windows-sso-to-psc-appliance/</guid>
      <description>This isn’t a be all and end all post on converting your Windows-based SSO server to the Platform Services Controller appliance, although I found an issue when performing the migration.
We kept receiving an “Update export failed” message when the appliance was deployed by the conversion wizard. We couldn’t understand why, and the appliance updaterunner.log file gave us no clues as to what it could be.
Turns out, you must run the vcsa_setup.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director and SAML Federation</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/vcloud-director-and-saml-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/vcloud-director-and-saml-federation/</guid>
      <description>I had a few issues getting vCloud Director and SAML federation playing nicely. By issues, I mean there wasn’t an explicit how-to in VMware’s doco. The big issues were group-based authentication and authenticating against a user&amp;rsquo;s email address instead of their UPN.
Using the following article from pablovirtualization I was able to get vCloud Director federated to an ADFS SAML endpoint.
https://pablovirtualization.wordpress.com/2015/01/13/vcloud-director-and-microsoft-ad-fs-active-director-federation-service-authentication/
This allowed users to login using their UPN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>