<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vcloud Director on Funky Cloud Medina</title>
    <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vcloud-director/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vcloud Director on Funky Cloud Medina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016-2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vcloud-director/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CassandraDB Shell - Unable to connect to any servers</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/cassandradb-shell---unable-to-connect-to-any-servers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/cassandradb-shell---unable-to-connect-to-any-servers/</guid>
      <description>One of the core pre-requisites for vCloud Availability for vCloud Director 2.0 is CassandraDB. This database service stores replication state and storage information and is used by the HCS (vSphere Replication Cloud Service) appliance.
As part of my strained vCloud Availability deployment I needed to build a simple CassandraDB server. VMware Docs and the vCloud Architecture blog have some great information to get you started:
 vCloud Architecture blog - Deploying CassandraDB VMware Docs - vCloud Availability for vCloud Director Installation Guide  Symptom I built the CassandraDB server as described in the blog post and Docs pages above, but when I would try to connect to the database using the Cassandra shell (cqlsh {ip-address} 9042) I would get the following error:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Availability - vCD Gateway creation failed</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/vcloud-availability---vcd-gateway-creation-failed/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2018/01/vcloud-availability---vcd-gateway-creation-failed/</guid>
      <description>After a short break over Christmas and New Year&amp;rsquo;s I threw myself into the latest version of vCloud Availability for vCloud Director (2.0).
The installation of vCloud Availability for vCloud Director (vCAv) is all done through an &amp;ldquo;installer appliance&amp;rdquo;, a CLI and a configuration file called a &amp;lsquo;registry&amp;rsquo;. I opted for the &amp;lsquo;automated&amp;rsquo; installation using a registry file and had all of my configuration and VM deployment specs in there.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CA-signed vCloud Director certificates no longer trusted – SAN missing</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/ca-signed-vcloud-director-certificates-no-longer-trusted--san-missing/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Jul 2017 17:43:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/07/ca-signed-vcloud-director-certificates-no-longer-trusted--san-missing/</guid>
      <description>Hello again! Today&amp;rsquo;s adventures drove me a little wild&amp;hellip;
Some background first. In my test environment, I have a full vCloud Director v8.10.1 deployment, load balanced with an F5 LTM. The certificates are loaded on the F5 so that traffic is terminated and re-encrypted on it&amp;rsquo;s way to the vCloud cells. Since deployment, both the http and console FQDNs functioned as expected. This all changed just a few months ago&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SYSTEM_REFRESH_VIMSERVER – Could not register vCloud Director as an extension to vCenter Server</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/system_refresh_vimserver--could-not-register-vcloud-director-as-an-extension-to-vcenter-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 13:30:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/system_refresh_vimserver--could-not-register-vcloud-director-as-an-extension-to-vcenter-server/</guid>
      <description>While trying to troubleshoot another problem, we tried Refreshing vCloud to vCenter which includes registering/updating the extension. This is when we hit a beauty we’d never seen before:
   Alright, calm down. Probably something with the network, right? And if it’s not the network then it’s probably DNS. Right? Oh how I wish that were so.
I dug around in the vCenter MOB and found the vCloud Director extension.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>‘java.lang.NullPointerException’ received when modifying objects in vCloud Director</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/java.lang.nullpointerexception-received-when-modifying-objects-in-vcloud-director/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Mar 2017 11:36:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/03/java.lang.nullpointerexception-received-when-modifying-objects-in-vcloud-director/</guid>
      <description>Roughly 2 weeks ago one of our vCloud Director tenants reported an error when attempting to increase a disk on their VM. They were told to contact their cloud administrator (yay). When we tried to perform the increase, we received an error we’d never seen before: “java.lang.NullPointerException”.
   Here is what we checked:
 Confirm the tenant Org vDC has the appropriate resources available (this was an ‘Allocation’ style vDC).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vCloud Director and SAML Federation</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/vcloud-director-and-saml-federation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/vcloud-director-and-saml-federation/</guid>
      <description>I had a few issues getting vCloud Director and SAML federation playing nicely. By issues, I mean there wasn’t an explicit how-to in VMware’s doco. The big issues were group-based authentication and authenticating against a user&amp;rsquo;s email address instead of their UPN.
Using the following article from pablovirtualization I was able to get vCloud Director federated to an ADFS SAML endpoint.
https://pablovirtualization.wordpress.com/2015/01/13/vcloud-director-and-microsoft-ad-fs-active-director-federation-service-authentication/
This allowed users to login using their UPN.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>