<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Vcsa on Funky Cloud Medina</title>
    <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vcsa/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Vcsa on Funky Cloud Medina</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2016-2017. All rights reserved.</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:00:00 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/tags/vcsa/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>vSphere 6 certificate templates with SHA256 encryption</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/01/vsphere-6-certificate-templates-with-sha256-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jan 2017 10:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2017/01/vsphere-6-certificate-templates-with-sha256-encryption/</guid>
      <description>I was just in the middle of configuring a PSC 6.0 node’s VMCA as an intermediate CA and, in traditional fashion, went to request a certificate from a Windows Server 2008 R2 Microsoft CA using the web enrollment form (as per this VMware KB article).
Oddly enough though my brand spanking new vSphere 6.0 machine and intermediate CA certificate templates were missing from the template selection drop down.
I had a look around online and found that MS CA v3 certificate templates are not supported in the web enrollment form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Update Export Failed – Converting Windows SSO to PSC Appliance</title>
      <link>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/update-export-failed--converting-windows-sso-to-psc-appliance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Dec 2016 17:00:00 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.funkycloudmedina.com/2016/12/update-export-failed--converting-windows-sso-to-psc-appliance/</guid>
      <description>This isn’t a be all and end all post on converting your Windows-based SSO server to the Platform Services Controller appliance, although I found an issue when performing the migration.
We kept receiving an “Update export failed” message when the appliance was deployed by the conversion wizard. We couldn’t understand why, and the appliance updaterunner.log file gave us no clues as to what it could be.
Turns out, you must run the vcsa_setup.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>